<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vaibhav Upreti</title>
    <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vaibhav Upreti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Week 6</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/gsoc-week6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/gsoc-week6/</guid>
      <description>GSoC Week 6 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Week 5 at CircuitVerse.org</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/gsoc-week5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/gsoc-week5/</guid>
      <description>Week 5 (26 June,23 - 2 July,23) During week 5, I devoted most my time to Mrsk &amp;amp; working on serving assets using ActiveStorage.
Mrsk Mrsk is a tool that allows you to deploy docker containers to bare metal servers, (or cloud VMs) using docker with zero downtime. Mrsk is still in aplha stage but is now in production at 37signals.
Before my GSoC coding period, I managed to explored this tool and deployed CircuitVerse using mrsk to a fresh EC2 instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Week 4: Distributed Tracing and Runbook Development</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/gsoc-week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/gsoc-week4/</guid>
      <description>OpenTelemetry For week 4 I spent most of my time working with Opentelemetry configuration for CircuitVerse.
OpenTelemetry is an observability framework and toolkit designed to create and manage telemetry data such as
traces metrics and logs OpenTelemetry can be used with a variety of backends, including open source tools like Jaeger and Prometheus, as well as commercial offerings like New Relic OpenTelemetry.
For Instrumentating a Rails app we would have to use opentelemetry-ruby sdk to create telemetry data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Distributed Tracing: Monitor your Rails app using Opentelemetry, Jaeger and New Relic Agent</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/distributed-tracing-opentelemetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/distributed-tracing-opentelemetry/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post we will learn how to instrument a Rails app using OpenTelemetry and send traces to Jaeger and New Relic simultaneously.
For additional information on OpenTelemetry, you can refer to my previous post.
Furthermore, basics are adequately covered in the OTEL docs
Without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s dive right into it.
Installing Required Gems Add these gems to your Gemfile
gem &amp;#34;opentelemetry-sdk&amp;#34; gem &amp;#34;opentelemetry-exporter-otlp&amp;#34; gem &amp;#34;opentelemetry-instrumentation-all&amp;#34; Once added bundle install</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Chronicles: Week 3</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/gsoc-week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/gsoc-week3/</guid>
      <description>Certainly the best week of my GSoC journey so far.
The changes that were merged this week will have a direct impact on hundreds of thousands of users. This is the first time I have pulled off such a task. I am thankful to my mentor Aboobacker for guiding me through it.
Despite numerous potential challenges, we effectively replicated attachments and seamlessly conducted data migrations, ensuring seamless transfer of previous data without any disruption or downtime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide to GSoC: Week 2, Don&#39;t Panic Edition</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/gsoc-week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/gsoc-week2/</guid>
      <description>It was an exhausting week filled with challenges, unexpected workload from college was overwhelming, leaving me with an awful lot of work to handle. On top of that, I had to juggle with my extracurricular commitments as well. It was a constant struggle to stay on top of everything and find a balance between my various responsibilities. I did manage to make good progress on my GSoC tasks, although I acknowledge that I still need to improve my time management skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Week1: Migrating assets to AWS S3</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/gsoc-week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/gsoc-week1/</guid>
      <description>Week 1 (29 May - 4 June) The Community bonding period was an incredible and refershing experience overall. I was excited and eager to start coding after the mentor meets. As a result I started coding few days before the actual period. This additional time was beneficial since the first task involves important production migration. Such tasks are not very straightforward, so the extra time allowed me thoroughly validate and test each part of my code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Bonding Period at CircuitVerse.org</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/community-bonding-period-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/community-bonding-period-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>What is Community Bonding Period? The Community Bonding Period typically spans several weeks leading up to the official start of coding in GSoC. It allows students to connect with their mentors and the open-source community. During this time, participants engage in various activities to familiarize themselves with the organization&amp;rsquo;s codebase, development processes, and community culture.
How did I spend it? During the initial days following the announcement of the GSoC results, contributors were assigned separate private channels for their respective projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey to GSoC 2023 with CircuitVerse.Org: How I Prepared and Applied for the Program</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/my-journey-to-gsoc-2023-with-circuitverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/my-journey-to-gsoc-2023-with-circuitverse/</guid>
      <description>What is Google Summer of Code? Google Summer of Code is a global, online program focused on bringing new contributors into open source software development. GSoC contributors work with an open source organization on a 12+ week programming project under the guidance of mentors.
Earlier this program used to be student only, but that barrier is no more and anyone can apply to GSoC. Read more about the eligibilty criteria</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customising Notification Events in Rails</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/circuitverse-customise-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 21:34:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/circuitverse-customise-notifications/</guid>
      <description>🎯 GOAL: Customise notification events
With reference to issue #3395 &amp;amp; PR #3396 in Circuitverse
There were two methods to make this work -
To make a preferences table with users as foreign key and notification events as attributes. To user rails ActiveRecord::Store and add a preferences hash/jsonb to users to table. I found the second approach better and implemented the same. It was most used by rails developers to implement such features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability Distribution with Python &amp; JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 21:34:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/statistics/</guid>
      <description>Probability distribution curve in Python and JS Consider 20 independent repetitions of drawing a bulb from a lot.
Probability that the bulb drawn will work for more than 500 hrs is 0.2.
Plot a probability distribution using python or scilab for getting k success in 20 trial
If I do something that has a constant probability of success - how many times do I need to do it to ensure that, on average, I&amp;rsquo;ll be successful?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>📙 About</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working with CircuitVerse this summer as a Google Summer of Code Student Developer.
Motivations If you’d like to know about my development career you can download my resumé.
OSS contributions Below you can find the list of my OSS contributions:
CircuitVerse At the moment, I am dedicating my time to delving into the inner workings of Rails and focusing on expanding my contributions to the project.
Socials LinkedIn GitHub Twitter Code Playlist Random Tweet British cuisine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🔗 Links</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/links/</guid>
      <description>Some links that I find useful
Programming Languages facingissuesonit : Facing Issues on IT - for java programming Ruby on Rails RubyGems : Find, install, and publish RubyGems. Rails Guide : Official Rails guide Books and Reading Libgenis : Download free eBooks - epub and pdf versions Code Repositories postgres-hll : Hll extension for postgres Awesome NOTION templates Note Taking System MacOS HomeBrew : The Missing Package Manager for macOS Random BBT Weekly Calender : Big Bang Theory Weekly Calender </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discuss</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/discuss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/discuss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Notifications in Simple Discussion Gem</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/simple-discussion-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/blog/simple-discussion-notifications/</guid>
      <description>🎯 GOAL Adding Notification Events to Simple Discussion
Adding two new notification events:
Notifying Admins on a new thread post Notifications to users that have subscribed to the thread New Thread notification: This sends notification to all moderators about a new thread, so that they can respond to the query asap.
For example in the following
for all admin users, moderators so that they can resolve the query asap. eg: ref, both the admin user receive notification when user1 posted a new thread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tags</title>
      <link>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaibhavupreti.github.io/hugo-blog/tags/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
